seekinghealth.com 2019-04-01

# Privacy Policy

## PRIVACY & SECURITY

### Privacy Policy for www.seekinghealth.com

Last updated: July 26, 2018

This Website collects some Personal Data from its Users. Users may be subject to different protection standards and broader standards may therefore apply to some. In order to learn more about the protection criteria, Users can refer to the applicability section.

### Privacy Notice for EU Data Subjects

If you are visiting this site from the European Union, please see our EU Data Subject Privacy Notice for information about the processing of your personal data.

#### Owner and Data Controller

Seeking Health LLC  
3140 Mercer Avenue  
Bellingham, WA 98225  
United States

**Owner contact email:** [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#34574147405b595146744751515f5d5a535c515558405c1a575b59)

### Children’s Privacy

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not knowingly collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.

If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

### California Online Privacy Protection Act

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. [See more here.](https://consumercal.org/about-cfc/cfc-education-foundation/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa-3/)

According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:

Users can visit our site anonymously.

A link to this Privacy Policy will be available on our home page.

Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’, and can be easily be found on the page specified above.

Users are able to change their personal information through our Service by: 

  * Emailing us
  * Calling us
  * Logging in to their account
  * Chatting with us or sending us a ticket

### CAN-SPAM Act

The CAN-SPAM Act sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, and gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them.

We collect your email address in order to: 

  * Send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions
  * Process orders and to send information and updates pertaining to orders
  * Market to our mailing list or continue to send emails to our clients after the original transaction has occurred

To be in accordance with CAN-SPAM we agree to the following: 

  * We do not use false, or misleading subjects or email addresses.
  * Messages are identified as advertisements in some reasonable way.
  * Messages include the physical address of our business headquarters.
  * We will honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.
  * We allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.

### Types of Data collected

Among the types of Personal Data that this Website collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: first name, last name, phone number, email address, Cookies, Usage Data, various types of Data, province, state, country, ZIP/Postal code, gender, city, address, date of birth and geographic position.

Complete details on each type of Personal Data collected are provided in the dedicated sections of this privacy policy or by specific explanation texts displayed prior to the Data collection.

Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or, in case of Usage Data, collected automatically when using this Website.

Unless specified otherwise, all Data requested by this Website is mandatory and failure to provide this Data may make it impossible for this Website to provide its services. In cases where this Website specifically states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to communicate this Data without consequences to the availability or the functioning of the Service.

Users who are uncertain about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact the Owner.

Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by this Website or by the owners of third-party services used by this Website serves the purpose of providing the Service required by the User, in addition to any other purposes described in the present document and in the Cookie Policy, if available.

Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through this Website and confirm that they have the third party’s consent to provide the Data to the Owner.

### Mode and place of processing the Data

#### Methods of processing

The Owner takes appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.

The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Owner, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of this Website (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third-party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Owner at any time.

#### Legal basis of processing

The Owner may process Personal Data relating to Users if one of the following applies: 

  * Users have given their consent for one or more specific purposes. Note: Under some legislations the Owner may be allowed to process Personal Data until the User objects to such processing (“opt-out”), without having to rely on consent or any other of the following legal bases. This, however, does not apply, whenever the processing of Personal Data is subject to European data protection law;
  * provision of Data is necessary for the performance of an agreement with the User and/or for any pre-contractual obligations thereof;
  * processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which the Owner is subject;
  * processing is related to a task that is carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the Owner;
  * processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner or by a third party.

In any case, the Owner will gladly help to clarify the specific legal basis that applies to the processing, and in particular whether the provision of Personal Data is a statutory or contractual requirement, or a requirement necessary to enter into a contract.

#### Place

The Data is processed at the Owner’s operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved in the processing are located.

Depending on the User’s location, data transfers may involve transferring the User’s Data to a country other than their own. To find out more about the place of processing of such transferred Data, Users can check the section containing details about the processing of Personal Data.

If broader protection standards are applicable, Users are also entitled to learn about the legal basis of Data transfers to a country outside the European Union or to any international organization governed by public international law or set up by two or more countries, such as the UN, and about the security measures taken by the Owner to safeguard their Data.

If any such transfer takes place, Users can find out more by checking the relevant sections of this document or inquire with the Owner using the information provided in the contact section.

#### Retention time

Personal Data shall be processed and stored for as long as required by the purpose they have been collected for.

Therefore: 

  * Personal Data collected for purposes related to the performance of a contract between the Owner and the User shall be retained until such contract has been fully performed.
  * Personal Data collected for the purposes of the Owner’s legitimate interests shall be retained as long as needed to fulfill such purposes. Users may find specific information regarding the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner within the relevant sections of this document or by contacting the Owner.

The Owner may be allowed to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever the User has given consent to such processing, as long as such consent is not withdrawn. Furthermore, the Owner may be obliged to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever required to do so for the performance of a legal obligation or upon order of an authority.

Once the retention period expires, Personal Data shall be deleted. Therefore, the right to access, the right to erasure, the right to rectification and the right to data portability cannot be enforced after expiration of the retention period.

### The purposes of processing

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its Services, as well as for the following purposes: Contacting the User, Interaction with external social networks and platforms, Analytics, Handling payments, Traffic optimization and distribution, SPAM protection, Managing contacts and sending messages, Social features, Managing support and contact requests, Interaction with live chat platforms, Registration and authentication and Location-based interactions.

Users can find further detailed information about such purposes of processing and about the specific Personal Data used for each purpose in the respective sections of this document.

### Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services: 

#### **Analytics**

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

###### Google Analytics (Google Inc.)

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Website, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/). [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en). Privacy Shield participant.

###### Analytics collected directly (this Website)

This Website uses an internal analytics system that does not involve third parties.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

###### Facebook Ads conversion tracking (Facebook, Inc.)

Facebook Ads conversion tracking is an analytics service provided by Facebook, Inc. that connects data from the Facebook advertising network with actions performed on this Website.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant.

###### HubSpot Analytics (HubSpot, Inc.)

HubSpot Analytics is an analytics service provided by HubSpot, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.hubspot.com/legal/privacy-policy) – Opt Out.

###### Google AdWords conversion tracking (Google Inc.)

Google AdWords conversion tracking is an analytics service provided by Google Inc. that connects data from the Google AdWords advertising network with actions performed on this Website.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant.

###### Rakuten (Rakuten, Inc.)

Rakuten is an affiliate management service provided by Rakuten, Inc. that connects data from the Rakuten affiliate network with actions performed on this Website, in order to calculate and disperse commissions to our affiliate partners.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States and other jurisdictions in accordance with Binding Corporate Rules (BCR) – [Privacy Policy](https://rakutenmarketing.com/legal-notices/website-privacy-policy).

#### **Analysis and predictions based on the User’s Data (“profiling”)**

The Owner may use the Personal and Usage Data collected through this Website to create or update User profiles. This type of Data processing allows the Owner to evaluate User choices, preferences and behaviour for the purposes outlined in the respective section of this document.

User profiles can also be created through the use of automated tools like algorithms, which can also be provided by third parties. To find out more, about the profiling activities performed, Users can check the relevant sections of this document.

The User always has a right to object to this kind of profiling activity. To find out more about the User’s rights and how to exercise them, the User is invited to consult the section of this document outlining the rights of the User.

#### **Contacting the User**

###### Contact form (this Website)

By filling in the contact form with their Data, the User authorizes this Website to use these details to reply to requests for information, quotes or any other kind of request as indicated by the form’s header.

Personal Data collected: email address, first name, last name and phone number.

###### Mailing list or newsletter (this Website)

By registering on the mailing list or for the newsletter, the User’s email address will be added to the contact list of those who may receive email messages containing information of commercial or promotional nature concerning this Website. Your email address might also be added to this list as a result of signing up to this Website or after making a purchase.

Personal Data collected: address, city, country, email address, first name, gender, last name, phone number, province, state and ZIP/Postal code.

###### Phone contact (this Website)

Users that provided their phone number might be contacted for commercial or promotional purposes related to this Website, as well as for fulfilling support requests.

Personal Data collected: phone number.

#### **Interaction with live chat platforms**

This type of service allows Users to interact with third-party live chat platforms directly from the pages of this Website, for contacting and being contacted by this Website support service. If one of these services is installed, it may collect browsing and Usage Data in the pages where it is installed, even if the Users do not actively use the service. Moreover, live chat conversations may be logged.

###### Zendesk Chat (Zendesk, Inc.)

Zendesk Chat is a service for interacting with the Zendesk live chat platform provided by Zendesk, Inc.

Personal Data collected: email address and first name.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/privacy-policy/). Privacy Shield participant.

#### **Managing contacts and sending messages**

This type of service makes it possible to manage a database of email contacts, phone contacts or any other contact information to communicate with the User. These services may also collect data concerning the date and time when the message was viewed by the User, as well as when the User interacted with it, such as by clicking on links included in the message.

###### HubSpot Email (HubSpot, Inc.)

HubSpot Email is an email address management and message sending service provided by HubSpot, Inc.

Personal Data collected: email address and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.hubspot.com/legal/privacy-policy).

#### **Registration and authentication**

By registering or authenticating, Users allow this Website to identify them and give them access to dedicated services. Depending on what is described below, third parties may provide registration and authentication services. In this case, this Website will be able to access some Data, stored by these third-party services, for registration or identification purposes.

###### Direct registration (this Website)

The User registers by filling out the registration form and providing the Personal Data directly to this Website.

Personal Data collected: date of birth, email address, first name, gender and last name.

#### **SPAM protection**

This type of service analyzes the traffic of this Website, potentially containing Users’ Personal Data, with the purpose of filtering it from parts of traffic, messages and content that are recognized as SPAM.

###### Google reCAPTCHA (Google Inc.)

Google reCAPTCHA is a SPAM protection service provided by Google Inc. The use of reCAPTCHA is subject to the Google privacy policy and terms of use.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/policies/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant.

#### **Handling payments**

Payment processing services enable this Website to process payments by credit card, bank transfer or other means. To ensure greater security, this Website shares only the information necessary to execute the transaction with the financial intermediaries handling the transaction. Some of these services may also enable the sending of timed messages to the User, such as emails containing invoices or notifications concerning the payment.

###### Authorize.Net (Authorize.Net)

Authorize.Net is a payment service provided by Authorize.Net.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.authorize.net/company/privacy/).

###### PayPal (PayPal Inc.)

PayPal is a payment service provided by PayPal Inc., which allows Users to make online payments.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: See the PayPal privacy policy – [Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/privacy).

###### Spreedly (Spreedly Inc.)

Spreedly is a payment service provided by Spreedly Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://spreedly.com/privacy).

#### **Interaction with external social networks and platforms**

This type of service allows interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of this Website. The interaction and information obtained through this Website are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network. This type of service might still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

###### Facebook Like button and social widgets (Facebook, Inc.)

The Facebook Like button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Facebook social network provided by Facebook, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation). Privacy Shield participant.

###### Google+ +1 button and social widgets (Google Inc.)

The Google+ +1 button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Google+ social network provided by Google Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/policies/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant.

###### Pinterest “Pin it” button and social widgets (Pinterest)

The Pinterest “Pin it” button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Pinterest platform provided by Pinterest Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://about.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy).

###### Twitter Tweet button and social widgets (Twitter, Inc.)

The Twitter Tweet button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Twitter social network provided by Twitter, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/privacy). Privacy Shield participant.

###### LinkedIn button and social widgets (LinkedIn Corporation)

The LinkedIn button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the LinkedIn social network provided by LinkedIn Corporation.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy).

###### YouTube button and social widgets (Google Inc.)

The YouTube button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the YouTube social network provided by Google Inc.

Personal Data collected: Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/). Privacy Shield participant.

#### **Location-based interactions**

###### Non-continuous geolocation (this Website)

This Website may collect, use, and share User location Data in order to provide location-based services.

Most browsers and devices provide tools to opt out from this feature by default. If explicit authorization has been provided, the User’s location data may be tracked by this Website.

The geographic location of the User is determined in a manner that isn’t continuous, either at the specific request of the User or when the User doesn’t point out its current location in the appropriate field and allows the application to detect the position automatically.

Personal Data collected: geographic position.

#### **Managing support and contact requests**

This type of service allows this Website to manage support and contact requests received via email or by other means, such as the contact form. The Personal Data processed depend on the information provided by the User in the messages and the means used for communication (e.g. email address).

###### Zendesk (Zendesk, Inc.)

Zendesk is a support and contact request management service provided by Zendesk Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.zendesk.com/company/privacy). Privacy Shield participant.

#### **Social features**

###### Inviting and suggesting friends (this Website)

This Website may use the Personal Data provided to allow Users to invite their friends - for example through the address book, if access has been provided - and to suggest friends or connections inside it.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data.

#### **Fraud protection**

This type of service analyzes the payment processing events of this Website, potentially containing Users’ Personal Data, with the purpose of filtering it from payment events that are recognized or suspected as fraudulent.

###### Kount (Kount, Inc.)

Kount is a fraud detection service provided by Kount, Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.kount.com/legal/privacy-policy). Privacy Shield participant.

#### **Traffic optimization and distribution**

This type of service allows this Website to distribute their content using servers located across different countries and to optimize their performance.

Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and the way these services are implemented. Their function is to filter communications between this Website and the User’s browser. Considering the widespread distribution of this system, it is difficult to determine the locations to which the contents that may contain Personal Information User are transferred.

###### CloudFlare (Cloudflare)

CloudFlare is a traffic optimization and distribution service provided by CloudFlare Inc. The way CloudFlare is integrated means that it filters all the traffic through this Website, i.e., communication between this Website and the User’s browser, while also allowing analytical data from this Website to be collected.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.cloudflare.com/security-policy/).

#### **Definitions and legal references**

##### Personal Data (or Data)

Any information that directly, indirectly, or in connection with other information — including a personal identification number — allows for the identification or identifiability of a natural person.

##### Usage Data

Information collected automatically through this Website (or third-party services employed in this Website), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use this Website, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server’s answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User’s IT environment.

##### User

The individual using this Website who, unless otherwise specified, coincides with the Data Subject.

##### Data Subject

The natural person to whom the Personal Data refers.

##### Data Processor (or Data Supervisor)

The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which processes Personal Data on behalf of the Controller, as described in this privacy policy.

##### Data Controller (or Owner)

The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the processing of Personal Data, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of this Website. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of this Website.

##### This Website (or this Application)

The means by which the Personal Data of the User is collected and processed.

##### Service

The service provided by this Website as described in the relative terms (if available) and on this site/application.

##### European Union (or EU)

Unless otherwise specified, all references made within this document to the European Union include all current member states to the European Union and the European Economic Area.

##### Cookies

Small sets of data stored in the User’s device.

##### Legal information

This privacy statement has been prepared based on provisions of multiple legislations, including Art. 13/14 of Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (General Data Protection Regulation).

This privacy policy relates solely to this Website, if not stated otherwise within this document.

### EU Data Subject Privacy Notice

This EU Data Subject Privacy Notice (“EU Privacy Notice”) explains how Seeking Health LLC (“Seeking Health”, “we”, “us”) fulfills our responsibilities under the EU General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) in relation to the collection, retention, use, and other processing of personal information that is obtained when EU data subjects visit and interact with our Website (www.seekinghealth.com) and use the Services.

#### Data Controller

Seeking Health LLC is the data controller for our Website and Services. You can contact us by e-mail sent to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#59292b302f383a20192a3c3c3230373e313c38352d31773a3634) or by writing to us at the following address:

Seeking Health LLC  
3140 Mercer Avenue  
Bellingham, WA 98225  
United States

#### Personal Data

We may collect and process the following personal data when you visit our Website and use our Services:

  * **Contact data.** You may provide us with your contact details, such as name, email address, physical address, phone number, email address, or other similar information, which we may use to respond to you or for administrative purposes.
  * **Log data.** As with most websites and technology services delivered over the Internet, our servers automatically collect information when you access or use our Website and record that data in log files. This log data may include your Internet Protocol (IP) address, the address of the web page visited before using our Website, browser type and settings, the date and time that the Website was used, information about browser configuration and plugins, language preferences, and cookie data.
  * **Device Information.** We may obtain information about devices that access our Website, including the type of device, its operating system, device settings, unique device identifiers, and crash data.
  * **Authentication Data.** To verify the identity of registered users on our Website and Services, we may collect a user name, password, password hint(s), and other similar authentication information.
  * **Other Information You Provide.** This includes emails and other communications that you send us or otherwise contribute, such as customer support inquiries and reviews. If you purchase a product, this will include information that is necessary to complete your purchase such as your credit card information.

We do not collect personal data that is considered to be sensitive or special categories of personal data under the GDPR.

Note that our Website and Services are dynamic. We may introduce new features, which may involve new or different personal data processing activities. If we make a material change to how we process your personal data, we will notify you and may also modify this EU Privacy Notice. If we have relied upon your consent for a particular use of your personal data, we will seek your consent to use such personal data for any other purpose.

#### How and Why We Use Your Personal Data

We may use the personal data we obtain to:

  * Communicate with you
  * Provide you with customized services
  * Ensure the security and integrity of our Website and Services
  * Maintain and promote our Website and Services
  * Analyze and learn about how our Website and Services are accessed and used
  * Manage our customer and partner relationships
  * Enforce our legal terms and policies
  * Protect our and others’ interests, rights, and property
  * Comply with applicable legal requirements.

#### Legal Bases for Processing Personal Data

We process your personal data pursuant to the following legal bases:

  * You have consented to the use of your personal data. When you consent, you can change your mind at any time.
  * The processing is necessary for us to provide you with the services and products you request, or to respond to your inquiries.
  * We have a legal obligation to process your personal data, such as to comply with applicable tax and other government regulations or to comply with a court order or binding law enforcement request.
  * To protect your vital interests, or those of others.
  * We have a legitimate interest in using your personal data. In particular, we have a legitimate interest in the following cases:  
1\. To analyze and improve the safety and security of our Website and Services. This includes implementing and enhancing security measures and protections and protecting against fraud, spam, and abuse.  
2\. To maintain and improve our Website and Services.  
3\. To operate our Website and Services and provide you with certain tailored advertising and communications to develop and promote our business.  
4\. To anonymize personal data and subsequently use the anonymized information. 

#### How We May Share Your Personal Data

We may share your personal data:

  * With our affiliates or business partners when it is reasonably necessary or desirable, such as to help provide services to you or analyze and improve the Website and Services.
  * With our service providers that perform services on our behalf. For example, we may use third parties to help us provide customer support, authorize and process your payments, manage our advertisements, send marketing and other communications on our behalf, or assist with data storage.
  * In order to follow the law or protect rights and interests. For example, we may disclose your personal data if we determine that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to comply with the law, protect our or others’ rights, property or interests, or prevent fraud or abuse. In particular, we may disclose your personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, such as to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
  * If we are involved in a reorganization, merger, acquisition, or sale of some or all of our assets.

#### How We Protect Your Personal Data

We maintain appropriate technical and organizational safeguards designed to help protect personal data from unauthorized disclosure or access and accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, or alteration. Although we use reasonable efforts to safeguard personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your information obtained through our Website and Services.

#### How Long We Retain Your Personal Data

We will store your personal data for no longer than is necessary for the performance of our obligations or to achieve the purposes for which the information was collected, or as may be permitted under applicable law. To determine the appropriate retention period, we will consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the information; the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of the information; the purposes for which we process the information and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means; and the applicable legal requirements. Unless otherwise required by applicable law, at the end of the retention period we will delete personal data from our systems and records or take appropriate steps to fully anonymize it.

#### How We Use Cookies and Other Similar Technologies

To improve our Website and Services, we may use “cookies” and other similar technologies to track your visit. Click [here](https://www.seekinghealth.com/cookies) to review our EU Cookie Policy.

#### Cross-Border Transfer of Personal Data

Please be aware that your personal data will be transferred to, processed, and stored in the United States. Data protection laws in the U.S. may be different from those in your country of residence.

When we transfer your personal data out of the European Economic Area (“EEA”) to countries not deemed by the European Commission (“EC”) to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data, including the United States, the transfer will be based on one of the following safeguards recognized by the EC as providing adequate protection for personal data, where required by EU data protection legislation:

  * Contracts approved by the EC which impose data protection obligations on the parties to the transfer.
  * The EU - U.S. Privacy Shield Framework (for transfers to third parties in the United States that have self-certified to the Framework).

Please contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used to transfer your personal data.

#### Your Rights

Under the GDPR, you have certain rights regarding your personal data. Subject to certain conditions, you may ask us to take the following actions in relation to your personal data:

  * Provide you with information about our processing of your personal data and give you access to your personal data.
  * Update or correct inaccuracies in your personal data.
  * Delete your personal data.
  * Transfer a machine-readable copy of your personal data to you or a third party of your choice.
  * Restrict the processing of your personal data.
  * Object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes.
  * Object to reliance on our legitimate interests as the basis for processing of your personal data.

To request a summary of your personal data, or to request revision or deletion of your personal data, please use our [Personal Information Request Form](https://www.seekinghealth.com/information-request/). You will be directed to log in to access the form to verify your identity and prevent fraudulent requests.

If you would like to submit a complaint about our use of your personal data or our response to your requests regarding your personal data, you may contact us by email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#95e5e7fce3f4f6ecd5e6f0f0fefcfbf2fdf0f4f9e1fdbbf6faf8), by writing to us at our postal address as provided below, or by submitting a complaint to the data protection regulator in your jurisdiction. You can find information about your data protection regulator [here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm).

#### How to Contact Us

You can contact us by e-mail sent to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#ed9d9f849b8c8e94ad9e88888684838a85888c819985c38e8280) or by writing to us at the following address:

Seeking Health LLC  
3140 Mercer Avenue  
Bellingham, WA 98225  
United States
